Freddy Thobhani

Full Stack Engineer

Email - bello@freddythobhani.com

I have been working professionally utilising my programming skills for the last four years to engineer robust Digital Systems. I enjoy collaborating with people and developing systems capable of creating an impact and always enthusiastic to learn new things.

Professional Work Experiences

Frontkom AS

Part-time Full Stack Developer December 2021 - Present

Responsibilities:

NodeJs, React Lead Developer

Apache Kafka data stream for database sync WebAssembly image manipulation on client-side

Projects Heartbeat Secure com.frontkom.heartbeat

Forbrukertilsynet

https://retusjert.forbrukertilsynet.no/

Technomedics

https://www.technomedics.no/

Green Doors LLC

Freelancer Full Stack Developer (via. Upwork)

March 2021 - February 2022

Responsibilities:

React Component/Feature development on Frontend Admin App

Backend API support

https://greendoorspm.com

Newslaundry - Reader supported Independent Media House

Software consultant and Freelance Full Stack Developer

May 2021 - September 2021

Responsibilities:

API/Webhook Integration to aggregate data from various sources.

Setup backend APIs Parse Platform

https://www.newslaundry.com

Code Symphony LLP

Fulltime Full Stack Developer & Teamlead

August 2018 - March 2021

Responsibilities:

Managing various client projects

Managing & Mentoring team of 4x Dev

Coding over **MERN** stack

React Native Development

Stripe Integration Firebase Firestore **Projects**

Eccocar

https://www.eccocar.com

Video Pipeline

https://videopipeline.io

Bluebird React Native App

com.pronunciatorllc.bluebird

Petaments petaments.de

Oizom Instruments Pvt. Ltd.

Software Development Intern

December 2016 - December 2017

Responsibilities:

Node Red Development

Tinkering IoT Projects (Arduino Development)

Python Development

https://oizom.com

Education

Østfold University College, Fredrikstad, Norway

Masters in Green Energy Technology Commencing September 2021

Government Engineering College, Modasa, India

Bachelors in Computer Engineering May 2016 - August 2020

St. Xavier's High School, Jamnagar, India

Higher Secondary Education June 2008 - March 2016

Shree Satya Sai Vidhyalaya, Jamnagar, India

Primary Education
June 2002 - March 2008

Courses & Certificates

Introduction To Interactive Programming with Python

Rice University (Coursera MOOC curriculum)

Python Data Structure

University of Michigan (Coursera MOOC curriculum)

Front-end Web UI Frameworks And Tools

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (Coursera MOOC curriculum)

Hobby Project

Mitti - Soil Sense

Nodemcu integration with sensors
Backend API with Parse Platform
React Native app to analysis data

An IoT device which can sense various factors in a farm like humidity, soil electrical conductivity, soil moisture, air pollution, solar radiation, and various nutrients.

Loo Project

Webapp using Node.js and Express.js

Aim of this project was to get crowd sourced data and map all the public toilets with information such as hygiene, accessibility, gender friendliness etc.

Vermicomposting

As part of family organic gardening goals successfully raised a colony of earthworms.

Winter Mountain Climbing

Trekking through Lord Curzon Trail to witness Mt. Nanda Devi, Kamet, Dronagiri, Hathi Parbat in all its Alpine glory. Winter - 2020

Girnar Summit Winter - 2020

Kederkantha Summit Attempt

Winter - 2019